Nick Karlaftis

Address: Adamantiou Korai 31A, Thessaloniki, GR

Mobile Phone: (+30) 6937183714 Email: NikoKarlS3@gmail.com

C# / .NET / SQL Developer

Eager to put .NET/SQL-oriented skills to use, utilising the advantages of Microsoft's latest technologies, to create reliable and high-standard applications.

Professional Profile

Accomplished C# developer with 5+ years' experience on full system development lifecycle, including designing and implementing various applications. My primary goal is to apply my technical expertise by bringing key principles of software engineering. One of my objectives is to be updated on the latest programming trends and technologies. My international experience and communication skills could be a multi applicable asset.

Areas of Expertise

| .NET Technologies & Frameworks | Software Application Tools |
|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| .NET Framework /.Net Core C# (LINQ, knowledge of functional paradigm) Dapper / EF Core Rest API (MediatR / Minimal APIs) Fluent Validation & Assertions Refit / Polly xUnit / NUnit | Visual Studio, VS Code, Rider Git, Tortoise SVN MS SQL, PostgreSQL Azure Cloud (basic) Azure DevOps (basic) Docker Postman / Redis |
| Software Architecture | Design Patterns-Principles |
| Clean ArchitectureDDD | SOLID PrinciplesVarious creational, structural and behavioural patterns |

Professional Experience

C# Developer • EmDot S.A. • Athens, GR December 2019 to present

Assist in the maintenance, development and evolvement of IoT related APIs, in the fields of waste management and roadside assistance.

Delivered solid software solutions for the shipbroking industry.

- Designed and implemented C# windows applications.
- Developed integration services/daemons using various APIs, ranging from mere vessel tracking up to more elaborate systems like XLedger ERP.
- Refactored and maintained legacy system and involved in migrating parts of it to a next generation system in .Net.
- Set up monitoring infrastructure system using Bosun and Docker hosted on an Azure Linux server.

Delphi Developer • Altec S.A. • Thessaloniki, GR

November 2010 to April 2011

My academic internship was fulfilled in the company Altec Software.

- Internship main task involved maintenance of an E.R.P.
- The tools used for the development were: Delphi 6, Microsoft SQL Server, PL/SQL.

Personal Projects

CRM for Pharmacy Store

December 2014 to January 2015

Designed and developed a commercial CRM desktop application for a pharmacy store. Comprehensively the application supports operations for Sales, Customers, Product and Charts. The application was implemented using the below tools: C# WinForms, MySQL

Education

2006 – 2012

Department of Informatics and Computer Technology, Technological Education Institute of West Macedonia, Kastoria (Greece)

National Service

• 2018 – 2019

Served in the Signals Arm as operator of digital terminal devices and cryptographic machines